the syntax for declaring a function is
solidity is straightforward functioning
data typing variable name for each input
order declaration like the keyword
public view peer and the type of outputs
to return and we be done with this video
if solidity functions were like other
programming languages in programming
language like JavaScript function can
take in data types like array and maps
as input and also return them as output
however you might be surprised and not
amused to find out that in solidity
public functions cannot accept certain
data types as input and you also cannot
return certain data type as outputs so
in this video let's explore the
restrictions on the type of inputs and
outputs for a public function and go
over the data types that you can use but
you really shouldn't use or at least be
extremely careful we'll also go over the
syntax for returning multiple outputs
from a function this is a useful feature
when you want to aggregate multiple
function outputs into a single function
call in solidity you can pass certain
data types as input to a public function
some data types that you cannot use our
map and multi-dimensional array without
a fixed size let's see what happens if
you try to compile contract with these
invalid inputs here we have a function
that takes a map as input let's try
compiling the contract
you'll get an error like the one you can
see here how about multi-dimensional
fixed sized array we'll compile it did
how about multi-dimensional dynamic
sized
array will this compile try compiling
the contract and you get our like the
one you can see here the error message
states that if you change the pragmatic
experimental avi encoder version two
then the function is valid code here
I've done exactly that change the pragma
inside the contract but as you can see
here in the warnings you should not
deploy a contract with experimental
features to the main net how about a
regular one dimensional array will
compile it does
so we've seen public functions can take
away as input but should you write
functions that take array of arbitrary
size in most cases the answer is no the
reason is simple guess the bigger the
array is the more gasket we use the
function will complete successfully for
some arrays and fail for other inputs
depending on the size of the array and
how much gas is available as a developer
this is difficult to predict up front
and it goes against the best practices
to write smart contracts that are simple
reliable and with predictable outcomes
one way to make this function more
reliable is to require that the size of
the array is less than some fixed number
this would put an upper bound to them
and I guess this function can possibly
use limitations on the outputs of a
public function is similar to that of
inputs outputs of type map and
multi-dimensional array with dynamic
size do not compile let's try them out
in remix back in our contract first
declare some datatypes a map an array a
multi-dimensional array of fixed size
and a multi-dimensional array without a
fixed size next let's see if these
functions that return different data
types can compile try compiling you will
see errors next to the function that
returns a map and also next to a
function that returns a
multi-dimensional array you will also
see error messages here below the
compile button and these errors are
similar to the ones we saw with invalid
inputs
solidity has no problem compiling a
function that returns an array but
should you write a function that returns
an array of unbounded size again the
answer is probably not what can go wrong
imagine there are two contracts a a and
B contract a has a function that returns
an array of addresses this function does
not create any transactions so you don't
have to worry about gas right wrong why
imagine contract B has a function that
calls contract a to get the array of
addresses and does something with it
like sending either to each other's now
what would happen if the array of
addresses in contract a is huge and
contract B tries to get it the function
in contract B will fail every time and
many people are unhappy that they can't
receive their either
so to summarize when writing smart
contracts you rather be safe than sorry
and one way to be safe is to write
functions that have a bounded
consumption of gas so little ease
limitation on public function is
inconvenient but one useful feature of
solidity is that you can return multiple
values and as a bonus they can be named
let's see an example in remix you can
declare that a function is returning
multiple values by listing the types of
values inside the parentheses after the
return keyword inside the function give
us the values to return outputs can also
be named like this also you can
explicitly assign to return variables
and omit the last return statement when
is it useful to return multiple outputs
it's useful when you want a function
that collect outputs of several
functions and return all of them in a
single function call let's say that we
have functions F and G one way to get
the outputs of F and G is to call the
functions individually that's two
function calls another way is to write a
function that calls F and G and returns
the two outputs in a single function
call how do you assign variables to the
output of a function that returns
multiple values you use destructuring
assignments it's easier to understand by
example then to explain what it is so
let's go through an example using actual
here were assigning the outputs of the
function return multiple bells notice
that the type of variables declared here
on the left side is consistent with the
type of values being returned from the
function being called you don't have to
assign all values if a function returns
three parameters but you don't care
about the second output this is how you
do it here you're telling solidity that
you need the first output not the second
so you may be declaring the type and
naming it and you also need the third
output
in this video we try to compile public
functions with different data types as
input in outputs in both cases maps
can't be used multi-dimensional fixed
size arrays can be used
multi-dimensional dynamic sized array
cannot array compiles but be careful and
you should put up a balance to the array
size we also learned how to write
functions that return multiple values
these outputs can be named or assigned
finally we saw how to assign variables
from a function that return multiple
values thanks for watching in the next
video I plan to cover peer and B
functions have a nice week and see you
soon