over here i have a deployed contract
the functionalities that this contract
provide is you can get the count
and you could increment the count so
let's say that i want to write a
contract
that interacts with this contract
without knowing the code of this
contract
but we do know the function signatures
of the functions that we want to call
we know that calling the function count
will give us back
a unit and we also know that calling the
function
increment will increment that count so
the question here is how do we write a
contract
that interacts with this contract
without having to copy paste
all the source code of this contract the
way you do it is by using interfaces so
in this video i'm going to show you how
to use the interface to
interact with the counter contract and
then we'll take a look at a real world
example
using uni swap to interact with our
example contract
we'll first need to write an interface
to the counter contract
and we do that by typing interface
i'll name this interface as i
counter and the two functions that we
want to call from the counter contract
is get the count and call the function
increment
so back in our i counter interface we'll
first
define the function count by saying
function count
external view and it returns
a uint and then we type in a semicolon
notice that unlike a contract we don't
define the function body
and we also put a semicolon after the
function signature
the other function that we want to call
from this counter contract
is the increment function so again here
we'll just define the function signature
by saying function
increment and
external and then we put a semicolon
so that's how you declare interface
let's now write our contract
that will actually make the calls to the
counter contract so inside my contract
i'll first write a function to call
increment on the counter
contract so we'll say function i'll name
it
increment counter
and it's going to take in the address of
the
counter contract this function will be
external
and the way you call the counter
contract is by saying i
counter at the counter address
and then we call increment
let's also get the count stored inside
the counter contract so we'll say
function get count
and again it's going to take the address
of the counter
and this is a read function that returns
a unit of the count
so you'll say external view
returns you
and and we'll say return
i counter at the counter
address dot count
and that's how you write a contract that
interacts with other contracts
without having to copy paste the code
for the contract that you're calling
and this is done by declaring the
interface and defining the function
signatures
for the functions that you want to call
inside your contract
all right let's see a demo in remix so
i'm gonna compile this code
and then deploy
my contract i'm gonna scroll down
first i'm gonna copy the address of the
counter contract
and then expand my contract and we'll
call
increment counter by passing in the
address that we just copied
and we can get the count by pasting in
the address of the counter contract
again
and we get the count two just to double
check
let's see what the count is on the
counter contract itself
so inside the counter contract i'll
click count
and it equals to over here too
next i'm going to show you example of
how to use interfaces
to interact with uni swap for this
example i'm going to show you how to get
the token reserve
of the die with pool in other words
we're going to get the amount of dye
and the amount of weft that is stored in
the uni swap
to get the token reserves the first
thing that we will need to do
is get the contract address that manages
these two tokens die and with
inside the uni-swap documentations if i
scroll down
i can see that this is the function that
i need to call
in order to get the contract addresses
that manages
die and with so i'm going to copy this
function signature
and back inside remix we'll define our
interface
so we'll say interface
uni swap version 2.
factory and then we'll paste the
function signature that we copied over
from the uniswap website
and calling this function will give us
back the contract address
that keeps track of how much dye and
weft
that is locked in unispot once we know
the contract address of the pair
we can get the token reserves by calling
get reserves
so i'm going to copy the function
signature here
and then inside remix we'll define an
interface
we'll call it uni swap b2
pair and then paste the function
signature
all right we define the interfaces we're
now ready to implement the
get token reserves so you'll get the
address of the pair by saying
address pair is equal to
uni swap version 2 factory
at the factory address
and then we'll call the get pair
function
passing in the address of die and
with once we have the pair address
we can get the reserves by saying
uint reserve
zero and you and
reserve one is
equal to
uni swap v2 pair
at pair and then calling get
reserves and then lastly we'll return
the reserves
so by saying reserve zero
reserve one let's go over what this
function does
it calls uni swap b2 factory
at the factory and gets the address of
the contract
that manages die and with
next we call get reserves on the pair
contract which returns the two token
amounts
managed under this contract and we just
returned the number
that was returned from here all right
let's see a demo in remix
so i'm gonna first compile this i forgot
to mention git reserve returns
three parameters but we don't need the
third one so here we'll say hey
ignore the third output all right let's
try compiling again
so i'm going to hit compile and then
under the tab to
deploy and run transactions i'm going to
click on
injected web 3 and this will connect
your meta mask to remix and we're now
connected to the mainnet network
now i don't want to waste either
deploying this contract
so what i'll do instead here is show you
how to use interface directly
to communicate with uni swap and we'll
manually go over the steps inside here
so the first thing that we'll need to do
is get the address of the pair
and we can do that by selecting
unison b to factory the address of the
factory is this
so i'm going to copy it
paste it here and then click address
this will get the contract at this
address
so i'm going to expand here and we can
get the pair
by passing in the address of
die and wef
and then calling get pair so that's the
address of the pair that i'm going to
copy
scrolling up we'll click on uni swap b2
pair
and then get the contract at the address
of the pair then call get reserves
so we just manually went through the
code over here
all right so that was an example of how
to use interface inside your contract
furthermore i showed you how to use
interfaces to directly
interact with smart contracts on the
main net
and we did that by using these
interfaces
and and directly pasting in the
addresses
thanks for watching and see you soon