in this video I'm gonna show you how to
sign and verify messages to assign a
message you first create a message to
sign and then you hash the message and
then you sign the hash of the message to
sign the hash you're gonna need your
private key of your eternium account and
you want to keep your private key or
secret so you will do the actual signing
without interacting with us my kata and
to verify a signature you will first
recreate the hash from the original
message and then you would recover the
signer from the signature and hash and
finally you would compare the recovered
signer to the claimed signer let's
imagine that we're signing a check from
a bank account so we need three
informations the person that were
signing the check to the amount that
this person can withdraw from our
account and what they don't know about
what this check is for and lastly we're
gonna need a unique identifier called
announce so that we can invalidate the
check wants the person withdrawals from
our account will declare this function
as public peer and it's gonna be tender
32 bytes hash of the inputs and inside
our get message hash function will
return the catch at 256 Bob our inputs
so this function here covers steps one
and two of signing now when we sign the
message - it's actually not the message
hash itself that is being signed what's
actually being signed is this you prefix
the message that you're going to sign
with ether um sign message followed by
the length of the message and then
finally the message itself you take all
of this and hash it using catch up to 56
and that is the message that is actually
being signed so when we sign the message
hash the actual message that will be
signed is the prefix
eternium sign message since the message
has is 32 bytes here the length will be
32 and then
followed by the message ash and then you
take the cat chapter 56 of the whole
thing so you'll write a function to
recreate that the input of this function
will be the message hash from the
function of up and since it's going to
create another hash it's going to return
by it's 32 inside the function it's
gonna return the catch up to 56 of the
prefix eternam sighing message followed
by the length of the message which will
be 32 and the actual message which is
going to be the message hash that is
passed from the input so that completes
the code for the function that recreates
the hash that is actually being signed
now to actually sign the message I'll
show you later
after we deploy this contract moving on
I'm gonna show you how to verify a
signature given a message hash first I'm
gonna write the function that paints the
big picture and then we'll work our way
down into the details to verify a
signature we need several inputs and the
address that claims to be the signer of
the message the parameters that was used
to create the message hash and the
signature itself and the function will
return true if the signer is indeed the
owner of the signature you'll first
recreate the message hash from the
inputs and then compute the hash that
was actually signed the function recover
signer which we all write out later will
take in the hash that was signed and the
signature and it will be turned the
address of the signer
so we are compared with the signer that
we think should have signed the message
and then we turn the comparison the
function recover Steiner is gonna fake
each side message hash and the signature
as input and it's gonna output an
address based on the message hash and
the signature to recover the signer we
first need to split the signature into
three parameters or s and B now you
don't need to understand what these
parameters
all you need to understand here is that
these parameters I needed to call the
built-in function EC recover to call the
function GC recover you first need a
pass in the hash that was signed and
then the parameter is B R in s that we
split from the signature and this
function will try to compute the address
that signed the hash and return a 0
address if the signature is invalid so
that completes the call to recover
designer let's now work on the function
split signature which we have not
defined yet the function split signature
is going to take the signature as input
and it's going to return the T
parameters are as can be needed to call
EC recover will first require that the
length of the signature is equal to 65
since 32 first output 32 for the second
output and 1 for the last output is
equal to 65 now to actually split the
bytes the only way to do it at this
moment is to use assembly and don't
worry if you don't understand this part
since you won't be using assembly much
now to get the first output from the
signature this is how you do it at X Y
will return X plus y so what does it
mean to that 32 to the signature well
you're not going to be adding 32 to the
actual signature signature is a dynamic
data type so what's being stored inside
the variable C is a pointer to where the
actual signature is stored in other
words the starting position of the
signature being stored in memory and
when you add 32 you move the starting
position by 32 effectively skipping the
first 32 bytes
why do you skip the first 32 bytes and
this is because dynamic array store the
length of the array in the first 32
bytes so the signature itself starts
after skipping the first 32 bytes
when you call the function endo with an
input of P it builds the next 32 bytes
starting at the memory address P so
putting it all together
this line of code will skip the first 32
bytes and then load the next 32 bytes
and then assign it to the variable R and
to get the value for the s we will do
something similar to what we did to get
the R value here we need to skip 64
bytes since the first 32 bytes stores
the length of the signature and the next
study 2 bytes stores the value for R so
the value for s starts after skipping
the first 64 bytes and to get the value
B we need to skip the first 96 bytes and
then get the first bite after so this is
how you get our SMB value from the
signature and that covers the code for
how to verify a signature let's now
compile and deploy the contract and I'll
show you example of how to sign and
verify a message and for this example
you're going to need meta mask which is
a eternium wallet that you can install
inside your browser so here I deployed
the contract I will create the message
hash to sign and then later verify the
signature and let's now go through these
steps first we'll create the message
hash to sign so you'll call the get
message hash function and for the inputs
I'll pass in the second account for the
number I'll pass in 1 2 3 4 the message
all passing in coffee and donuts and
then for the nouns or pass in one and
then call the function and that's the
hash that we're going to be signing and
to sign the hash we need to allow remix
to connect to metal mask and you can do
that by hitting f12 and opening the
JavaScript console and then typing the
30 end of enable this will open up the
metal mask so go ahead and type in your
password to unlock it and then hit
connect so now you'll have access to
meta mask inside the browser console and
we can sign the hash inside the browser
now first of all assign the hash to a
variable named hash and to sign the hash
you'll need to call what the personal
dot sign pass in the hash followed by
the account that we're going to use to
sign - in this case we will use the
default account that is available to
meta mask and you can access that by
calling web 3.8 the default hotel and
then finally we will console the result
so you'll see a pop-up like this and hit
sign and that is our signature and the
signature will be different for
different accounts now to verify the
signature we're gonna need the address
of the signer and we can get it by
calling web 3 the the default account
again so that was the address that was
used to sign the message and to verify
the signature I'm gonna paste the signer
in here and then passing the parameters
that was used to sign it and then the
signature itself
then head verified and you can see that
the function verified
returned to now if you change the
parameter even by a little for example
instead of sending one two three will
add extra zero and then hit verify and
you can see that the function returns
false likewise if we keep the message
the same but changed the signature so
for example changing the signature by
one number and then hit verify it would
again return false so in summary if you
changed the original message or the
signature even by a little bit then the
signature is no longer valid that's all
I got to say about signature
verification thanks for watching and
have a nice day