functions can be declared to have
certain visibility like public private
internal and external functions can also
be declared to have certain behavior
like boo peer and payable in this video
we're gonna go over what beyou and peer
functions are functions declared with
the keyword view promised not to modify
the state of the blockchain according to
the solidity documentation the following
are considered to modify the state of
the blockchain writing to state
variables emitting events also known as
logging this is a topic for another
video creating other contracts using
self-destruct this is a function to call
when you want to delete your contract
from the blockchain sending either by
calls in other words calling the
function to send either to another
address calling any function not marked
as view or peer using low-level calls
and using inline assembly that contains
certain op codes so if a function is
marked as Bude then that function cannot
contain any code that does any of
actions mentioned here let's go over
some examples in remix first we will
walk through an example of a ballad view
function next we're going to try
compiling the function declared as view
but inside the function we're going to
modify the state variable and we're also
going to try to compile function again
declare this view but inside the
function we're going to call another
function which is neither Beauty nor
peer first let's see an example of AB
you function that does keep the promise
not to modify the state here we have a
state variable named X initialized to
the value 1 we also have a function
named add to X add to X takes in an
integer variable named Y as input and
returns a sum of X plus y where X is the
state variable this is a ballot view
function since it reads the state
variable X but does not update it we can
verify that calling this function does
not update the state variable X compile
and deploy the contract
next let's check the value of X it
should be one which is what we
initialized it to we'll call this
function later again and verify that the
state variable was not modified next
call add to X with some input you'll get
the sum of X plus your input at the
bottom of the remix console you'll
notice that calling this function did
not create any transactions as long as
the function does not create any
transactions there is no way to change
the state of the blockchain so calling
add to X did not modify any state to be
100% sure let's double check on the
state variable X and make sure that it
hasn't changed it's still 1 what would
happen if we declare a function as view
but inside the function modify the state
variable let's give it a try create a
function called update X and declare as
view we're going to violate the promise
not to modify the state inside the
function update the state variable X by
incrementing it and hit compile you'll
see a compilation error like this this
is a really good feature of solidity
that it can detect potential state
changes a function cannot be AB u
function if it calls another function
which is neither bill nor peer here we
have a function called foo and it is not
declared as view we also have a function
called invalid view func which is
declared as view inside the function
invalid be func it's going to call
another function foo which is neither
Beauty nor peer if you try to compile
this code you'll get a error like this
stating that invalid view func
contains code that potentially modifies
the state
view functions declare not to modify the
state peer functions make a stronger
promise peer functions promise not to
modify state like B functions in
addition they also promise not to read
the state according to the solidity
documentation the following are
considered reading from the state
reading from state variables accessing
the ether balance urban address reading
from special variables like blog TX and
message calling any function not marked
peer and using inline assembly
containing certain op codes so a peer
function cannot contain any code that
does any of the actions mentioned here
and it can also modify the state like a
b function let's see some examples of
peer function in remix first we'll go
over an example of a ballot peer
function next we'll see some examples of
invalid peer functions here is an
example of a ballot peer function here
we have a function named ad ad is a
function that takes two inputs I and J
and returns I plus J this is a ballot
peer function since it doesn't read any
state and modify any state next let's
see some examples of invalid peer
functions revisit the add two function
back at the top of the contract this is
a ballad view function however since it
reads from the state variable this
cannot be a peer function let's declare
as peer anyways and hit compile you'll
see a similar error to the ones we got
when we try to compile invalid view
function
similar to how AB you function can only
call other view or peer functions appear
functions can only call other peer
function so a function declared as peer
but if it calls a non peer fortune then
it is invalid code let's see an example
here we have a function foo which is
neither Beauty nor peer and we also have
a function invalid peer func declared as
peer inside this function foo is called
since foo is neither Beauty nor peer
this contract will not compile the code
becomes valid when you declare foo as a
peer function so we've just seen that a
peer function can only call other peer
functions it's easy to forget to declare
a function as B or peer the good news is
that the solidity compiler is smart
enough to warn you that you might have
forgotten to put these keywords on your
functions when you compile your contract
and remix you'll get warning stating
that functions can be declared as view
or peer so don't forget to carefully
check the warnings and fix your code if
necessary
in this video we cover beer and peer
functions beautiful chains promise not
to modify the state peer functions make
a stronger promised and view functions
they promise neither to modify the state
nor read the state thank you so much for
watching and I'll see you next time